METER主席声明
白宫是否用游说来阻止家庭第一提案?
你知道在第一家庭提案投票的那天
Did you know what was going on in your name
有些人以你的名义做了一些什么吗?
on the day of the Families First vote?
你是不是在用说客游说?
Were you using lobbyists?
我永远不会让这种事情发生
I would never, ever let that happen.
而且就算它发生了 当然绝对不可能发生
And if it had happened, which it absolutely did not,
我也一定会采取某种措施的
I would make sure that something was done about it.
非常极其的肯定
Absolutely damn sure.
所以这对于国会来说不算是个麻烦?
So this wasn't a matter for Congress?
嗯 我确定国会的各位
Well, I am certain that Congress,
还有我的反对者们 与其关注这件事
and my opponents for that matter,
不如用他们的时间做更好的事
have better things to do with their time,
比如好好处理一下政府的事宜
like getting down to the business of government.
然后再让我向美国人民重申一次
And let me repeat myself again and say to the American people
这些没有根据的指控不具有任何一点点的真实性
that there is not one ounce of truth to these allegations.
- 总统女士-- - 不具有
- Madam President-- - Not
任何一点点的真实性
one ounce of truth to these allegations.
非常感谢 今天就到这里
Thank you very much. That's all the time I have for today.
- 谢谢
- Thank you.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
你是否向上帝发誓
Do you solemnly swear
你尽其所知
that the testimony you're about to give is the truth,
所述之言纯属实言并且无任何隐瞒?
the whole truth, and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- 我发誓 - 是的 我发誓
- I do. - Yes, I do.
完全同意 是的 先生 我发誓
Absolutely. Yes, sir, I do.
Cafferty先生 请恕我直言
Mr. Cafferty, pardon me being blunt,
为什么家庭第一提案没有通过?
but why did Families First fail?
这种事经常发生 就像天会下雨
It happens. Rain gonna fall,
议院司法委员会听证会
白宫是否利用游说者来使它们的提案失败?
酒吧会关门 提案也会被砍
bar's gonna close, bill's gonna fail.
Cafferty先生真会说话 出口成章
There's a job for you at Hallmark, Mr. Cafferty.
法案没通过你看起来好像也不怎么伤心
You don't seem upset that the bill failed.
如果我有孩子的话 顺便一说我还真有
If I had kids, which actually I do,
这个提案就是我的小宝贝
this bill would be my baby.
我和整个白宫
I and the entire White House,
我们一起在挥洒汗水呕心沥血
we sweated a full transfusion of blood
想让这个提案通过
to pass this bill.
不是说Jonah Ryan并非受命支持法案的
So Jonah Ryan wasn't sent here to defend the bill,
而是故意来捣乱的吗?
to deliberately undermine it?
不 不 请看我性感的唇 不
No. No. Read my luscious lips, no.
我们是顾问 而不是说客
We were consultants, not lobbyists.
所以区别在哪?
And what's the difference?
如果你要求咨询
You ask to be consulted.
顾问会给客户提建议
A consultant consults the client,
然而说客是代表客户游说
whereas a lobbyist lobbies on behalf of the client.
你没跟我说区别啊
You're nrot telling me the difference,
你只是把名词改动词了
you're just turning nouns into verbs.
所以你在建议别人
So you were consulting
给家庭第一提案投反对票?
people to vote against the Families First Bill?
是的 是的 我们就是这么做的
Yes. Yes, we were.
这确实就是他们一直在干的事
That's exactly what they were doing.
抱歉 Ryan先生 我们没问你的意见
Excuse me, Mr. Ryan. We didn't ask for your commentary
或是让你证明他们的证词
on the veracity of their testimonies.
哦 我很抱歉 先生
Oh, I'm very sorry, sir.
我很抱歉我的不当行为
I'm sorry that I misconducted myself
我以后不会这么做了
and I will not do that in to the future.
你对于Brookheimer女士和Egan先生的评价是什么?
What is your assessment of Ms. Brookheimer and Mr. Egan?
噢 Brookheimer女士是一个坚强
Oh, Ms. Brookheimer is a strong,
独立 处事灵活的女性
independent, flexible woman.
并且上帝知道华盛顿就缺这种类型的
And Lord knows there aren't enough of those in DC.
Egan先生呢?
And Mr. Egan?
呃 Dan Egan大概十分里面能给五分半 不太够六分吧
Uh, Dan Egan is a solid five and a half, weak six.
你能告诉我们是谁导致了数据的泄露吗?
Can you tell us who was responsible for the data breach?
不能 呃 我指 是的
No. Well, I mean, yes.
是的 公众都知道
Yes, it's a matter of public record
Dan Egan因为和数据泄露有关
that Dan Egan was fired
所以被炒鱿鱼了
because of his relation to the data breach.
我是指 你百度一下也会知道啊
I mean, you could have Googled that.
等下 这不是我的问题
Wait, that's not my question.
他是否应该为数据泄露负责?
Was he responsible?
华盛顿需要一个牺牲
Washington needed a sacrifice,
所以我们都跑去拿出我们的草耙子
so we all ran and took out our pitchforks
然后点火把柴火Dan给烧了
and we set fire to the wicker Dan.
哦 那如果他是无辜的话 为什么要离开?
Okay, so why did he deserve to go if he was innocent?
你说的好像应该发生的和实际发生的
You make it sound like there's a correlation
有关联一样
between what should happen and what actually happens.
我是想说 生活如此混乱 总有不公平
I mean, life is chaotic and it's often unfair.
至少我就是这样
I know it is for me.
Dan Egan活该离职
Dan Egan deserved to go,
所以他离开了
so he went.
我承认我喜欢钱
Sure, I love money.
但我还爱别的
But there's something else that I love
那就是这个叫美利坚合众国的小姑娘
and it's a little lady called the United States of America.
而今天我和Brookgheimer女士在此正是作为爱国者的身份
And Ms. Brookheimer and I are here today as patriots
来为平常百姓说话
speaking up for the common citizen,
为个人亦或是公司
be that individual an actual person or a corporation.
拔高自己硬装逼
That shoehorned stab at nobility
- 在这儿是行不通的- 明白
- will not fly here. - Okay.
Brookheimer女士 你们是纯粹只认钱吗?
Ms. Brookheimer, are you guided purely by money?
我觉得很有趣
I think it's interesting
你居然选择我来回答这个问题
that you chose me to aim that question at,
仿佛是在暗示 我就是个唯利是图
insinuating that I am a money-grabbing,
一心追求名利, 没有道德水准的人
careerist, low-moraled--
我不知道为什么我居然在帮你说话
I don't know why I'm helping you here.
Brookheimei女士 你声音没有必要那么尖厉
There is no need to be shrill, Ms. Brookheimer.
- 有吗? - 嗯
- Shrill? - Mmm.
你是否还记得一份分享在J盘上
Do you recall a document shared on the J-drive
名为 Jona蛋的文档
titled the Jonad Files?
- 呃 不 不记得 女士 - 不 没有什么印象
- Uh, no. No, ma'am. - No. That doesn't ring a bell.
所以Jona蛋也不是Jonah和蛋蛋的组合词?
So it's not a word combining Jonah and gonad?
- 据我所知并不是这样 - 我能证明
- Not to my knowledge. - I can confirm
事实上就是那样 并且Egan先生他也知道
that that is exactly what it is and Mr. Egan knows that.
事实上, Egan先生, 我还被告知你鼓励身边的职员们
In fact, Mr. Egan, I was told that you encouraged staffers
加入到侮辱性词汇的使用中
to add to this glossary of abuse.
我现在一时半会儿真想不起来我有这么做过
I do not at this moment in time recall the action
也不记得你问的那个文件
nor the document in question.
好吧 可能这个能激发你的记忆 我们摘录了几段
Okay, maybe this will jog your memory. We have some extracts.
J硬棍 精精?吉莱斯皮(原为"Dizzy" Gillespie爵士歌手)，杰克和撸管巨人
J-Rock, Jizzy Gillespie, Jack and the Giant Jackoff,
基星人(alien) 修蛋精灵(Tinkerbell) 精丝拉(哥斯拉) 单勃乐队(One Direction单向乐队)--
Gaylien, Tinker Balls, Wadzilla, One Erection--
我们非得把这些都念出来吗?
Do we have to go through all of these?
我从中并看不出有什么关联
I'm not sure that I see the relevance.
证人们声称他们对他们前同事十分尊敬
The witnesses claim they held their former colleague
我这是在尝试证明事实并非如此
in high regard and I am attempting to prove otherwise.
好吧 没错 是这样 那行 你继续吧
Okay, yeah, sure. No, you can proceed.
废话怪 巨型处男
The Pointless Giant, The 60-Foot Virgin,
大精精(chimpanzee) 哦不Jonah 海格的阴囊(哈利波特人物)
Gimpanzee, Jonah Ono, Hagrid's Nutsack,
鸡巴蛋 变性金刚
Scrotum Pole, Transgenderformers,
为奴撸管十二年
12 Years a Slave to Jerking Off,
圣自渎规则(圣本笃规则)
Benedict Come In His Own Hand,
摩基楼(Skyscraper) 雷震子
Guyscraper, The Cloud Botherer,
难以置鸡精菜绝伦(Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious魔法保姆)
Supercalifragilisticexpiali- Dick Cheese,
忍者菊龟 喷精卡(chewbacca星战)
Teenage Mutant Ninja Asshole, Spewbacca.
我的同事都叫我"加长版McCartney"(甲壳虫乐队一员)
My college friends called me Tall McCartney.
我更喜欢这个 这是个好昵称
I preferred that. That's a good nickname.
难以控制的裂缝已经在你们的关系里产生
Fractious cracks have opened up in your relationships
这同时也反应在了你的证词里 这些我们会在接下来的审议中深究
and in your testimony and we'll explore them in a later session.
你是否向上帝发誓
Do you solemnly swear that
你尽其所知
the testimony you're about to give is the truth,
所述之言纯属实言并且无任何隐瞒?
the whole truth, and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
我愿意
I do.
你是在四月从白宫被解雇 请问这是否属实?
You were fired from the White House in April. Is that correct?
是的  但我戏虐的内心更喜欢把这称为
Yes. The drama queen in me likes to say
他们在复活节把我给祭了
that they sacrificed me at Easter.
呃 你一直外界被认为是替罪羊
Uh, you've been described as the scapegoat.
那事实上你是否对这次的HIV数据泄露有责任?
Were you in fact responsible for the HIV data breach?
没有 我向来很注重保密
No, I value confidentiality
但自相矛盾的是 我并不注重谁知道我这一点
and paradoxically I don't care who knows it.
那你为什么被解雇呢?
Why were you fired?
为了掩盖这背后更大的秘密
To conceal something bigger.
他们把我当耗子一样不当回事
They thought I was a mouse.
但他们错了 这只老鼠是会咆哮的
Well, this mouse will roar.
Patterson女士 你最好跟我们说说那个更大的秘密
Ms. Patterson, you better tell us what that something bigger is.
竞选活动中的某人使用了联邦数据泄露事件中的
Someone from the campaign used child mortality data
儿童死亡率的数据
from the same federal breach
就是说Jennifer Grahm是艾滋病童的同一批数据
that named Jennifer Graham as an HIV victim.
使用该数据是为了什么目的?
Used to what end?
为了故意给丧子的家长们
To deliberately target bereaved parents
发送一封名为 我在乎 的竞选邮件
for a campaign mailer called I Care.
好的 接下来我会这么做
Okay, so this is how it's gonna work.
证词
我会把你们想要的一切放在一个
I'm gonna give you everything you need in a nice little box
用红丝带系着的小盒子里
with a pretty red ribbon on
之后我就重获自由 好吗?
it and then I'm gonna walk away a free man, okay?
- 麻溜儿的 行吗? - 开始吧
- Rat and roll. Deal? - Go on.
关于Lee Patterson--
The thing about Lee Patterson--
她根本不知道自己怎么就成了替罪羊
she doesn't even know why she was scapegoated.
好吗? 但我知道 是因为那份儿童死亡数据的用途是--
Okay? I do. It's because the child mortality data was used--
对 是为了拉拢痛失孩子的父母们 我们已经知道了
Yeah, was used to target bereaved parents. We know that already.
Ms. Patterson's现在正在接受委员会的询问
Ms. Patterson's talking to the committee right now.
是的 - 好吧 再说点深入的
Yes. - Okay, going deeper here.
那份数据其实是是和--
That data was actually taken from the same--
恩 是和那个艾滋病女孩事件
Yeah, it was from the same breach
出自同一次数据外泄
which identified the HIV girl.
- 我们也都知道了 - 嗯哼
- We know all that. - Mm-hmm.
各位 我们的协议还有效 是吧?
Guys, we still have a deal, right?
你意识到你对这次数据外泄的指认
Ms. Patterson, you are aware that your accusations
将对你和其他人
about the data breach will
都产生十分严重的影响
have serious repercussions for you and the others?
我明白之中的危险
I understand the dangers
也明白您提醒我的好意
and how you're well-placed to remind me of them.
你是在暗示我和总统夫人的私人友谊
You're insinuating that my close personal friendship
影响了我的判断力?
with the president might cloud my judgment?
不是 完全不是
No, not at all.
女士 您的判断力 是无可挑剔的
Your judgment, ma'am, is unimpeachable.
总统夫人了解这次数据外泄吗?
Did the president know about the data breach?
不 只是她身边的那些人
No, just the people around her.
Bill Ericsson和Gary Walsh与她最为亲近
Bill Ericsson and Gary Walsh were closest to her.
这就是我为什么知道Bill Ericsson--
Which is how I know that Bill Ericsson--
了解数据外泄的事
Knew about the data breach.
您脑子里的信号是不是有点延迟了 Mr. Egan?
Are you on some kind of satellite delay, Mr. Egan?
没有对Lee Patterson女士不敬的意思
With respect to Lee Patterson,
但她完全不明白都发生了什么
she had no real idea, no concept of what was actually happening.
我是说 她级别太低了
I mean, she was so junior,
她也许还同时在后厨工作呢
she may have well been working in the kitchens,
我没有瞧不起厨房工作的意思
with all due respect to the kitchens.
我郑重声明 Ms. Patterson是一名非常有能力的员工
But for the record, Ms. Patterson was a very competent staffer
她就是Jimmy Cagney口中的那些
and what Jimmy Cagney would have called
好孩子 在我看来
a good kid in my opinion.
我等着被提问吧
I'll wait for a question.
我们有一位证人的证词
We have a deposition from a witness
指认你 Mr. Ericsson
confirming that you, Mr. Ericsson,
安排Dan Egan去开除Ms. Patterson
ordered Dan Egan to fire Ms. Patterson.
这就是我所害怕的 我正在被滚雪球
This is what I was afraid of. I'm being snowballed.
- 我是滚雪球的牺牲者 - 你是什么意思Mr. Ericsson?
- I'm a victim of snowballing. - What do you mean, Mr. Ericsson?
就是一个名字被提了 就会反复被提
Well, a name gets mentioned, then gets mentioned again,
不久所有人都会提
and pretty soon everyone is mentioning it
然后所有的事都像雪球越滚越大
and then the whole thing snowballs
最后雪球汇聚成一场雪崩
and then there's an avalanche of snowballs
我就被别人的雪活埋了
and I'm being buried by other people's snow
还不是纯白的雪
and it's not pure driven,
我说的也不是真的雪 如果您明白我的意思
it's not white snow, if you catch my drift.
我一定给他们说明白了 我说明白了吗?
I certainly caught their drift. Do I make sense?
- 我讲通了吗? - 冷静-- 冷静一下
- Am I making sense? - Calm-- calm down.
你开除Lee Patterson女士
Isn't snowballing
的行为不就是在向她滚雪球吗?
what you did to Lee Patterson when you had her fired?
不 那是栽赃
No, that was scapegoating.
再一次道歉
Again, apologies.
您并没有向我提问
You haven't asked me a question.
栽赃和滚雪球效应 两者有什么区别吗?
What is the difference between scapegoating and snowballing?
栽赃与我无关 这就是区别
It's not my fault. That's the difference.
这个-- 这讲通了吗?
Is that-- is that making sense?
那不是我的错 我的重点是这个
It's not my fault is my basic point.
我想说 我身边坐的就是一位竞选经理
I mean, why I am being raked over the coals
为什么泄露的数据
for the misuse of data in the
被竞选活动滥用 却只有我被谴责?
campaign when I'm sitting next to the campaign manager?
噢 这真是-- 好样的 Bill 干得好
Oh, that's-- bravo, Bill. Subtly done.
Mr. Davison 你是President Meyer的竞选经理 是吧?
Mr. Davison, you are President Meyer's campaign manager, yes?
是的 女士 但不是在数据泄露的时候
Yes, ma'am. Though not at the time of the breach.
然而你当时已经意识到了事态的发展
But you were aware of it at the time
却选择缄口不言?
and yet you chose to say nothing?
那个时候 在表面上还看不出什么端倪
Well, though it may appear that there was nothing going on,
但我可以向您保证有--
I can assure you that there was--
有很多事情正在暗地里发生
there was lots going on underneath.
,就像天鹅和霍金教授一样看不出动作
Like a swan or Professor Hawking.
还有谁参与了?
Who else, then, was involved?
证词
Gary Gary Walsh
Gary. Gary Walsh.
总统夫人的提包男?
The president's bagman?
是 他就像是那种人
Yeah, he's the guy.
但是-- 你看过"非常嫌疑犯"吗?
But-- okay, you ever seen "Usual Suspects"?
没有看过
I haven't seen it.
好吧 他就像是Keyser-- 我是说--
Okay, well, he's Keyser-- I mean--
你没看过 算了
you haven't seen it, so forget it.
Gary就是那个拖我和Amy Brookheimer下水的人
Gary's the guy who got Amy Brookheimer and I involved.
他是个提包男 对 但他也是个坏人
He's the bagman, yeah, but he's also the bad man.
Walsh先生 有些人
Mr. Walsh, several people
现在认为你是整个事件的核心人物
have now described you as being at the center of events,
所以我想知道你是否能描述一下
so I was wondering if you could please outline to us
你的工作职责
your duties and your responsibilities.
Walsh先生 有什么问题吗?
Is there a problem, Mr. Walsh?
抱歉 我只是--
I'm sorry. It's just when I was--
最初我被传唤过过来 只说是一个小型听证会
when I was originally summoned, it was a smaller hearing
我放弃行政豁免权就来了
and executive privileges were waived
而现在这里就像周杰伦演唱会现场
and now it's like a U2 concert.
好了 我们正在调查你的玩忽职守
Well, we are investigating malpractice
看你是不是犯了罪需要刑事调查
possibly leading to criminal investigation.
你需要履行你的行政豁免权么?
Might you unwaive your executive privilege?
呃哈 他说不 所以...
Uh-huh. He says not to, so...
你和Dan Egan关系不错?
Would you say you were friendly with Dan Egan?
是 我和他关系不错
Yes, I'm friendly with Dan Egan.
我-我们是朋友 对
I-- we're friends, yes.
在第一家庭提案投票的那天
You were seen with him and Amy Brookheimer
有人看到你和他还有Amy Brookheimer在一起
on the day of the Families First vote.
对
Yeah.
Dan不是我的朋友
Dan is not my friend.
他只是我的同事
He's a colleague.
我不知道为什么我刚刚说我俩是朋友
I don't know why I said we were friends.
我的错-- 只是我相信
That's a fault of mine-- just kind of believing
有些人曾经是朋友 而现在不再是朋友
that people were friends and they're not friends.
自我中学年代起就是这样了
It's kind of been going on since middle school
你正好让我不恰当的时候说漏了嘴
and you just caught me at a bad time.
你和Egan先生保持距离可能是明智的
You're probably correct to distance yourself from Mr. Egan.
那你怎样描述
How would you describe
你和总统之间的工作关系?
your working relationship with the president?
呃 非常亲密
Uh, it's very intimate.
我经常把自己当做是一个信息渠道
I've always imagined myself as like a pipeline
我收集很多重要信息
who carries a lot of necessary information
并且直接将信息传送给总统
and I just feed it directly into her head.
证词
总统女士 我想确认你是否已经放弃了你的总统行政特权?
Madam President, can I confirm you've waived executive privilege?
是的
Yes.
我可以告诉你
Though it is no privilege to have to endure
虽然此次调查中不需要任何特权
this investigation, I can tell you that.
但我很高兴我能够协助调查
But I'm happy to assist in any way that I can.
- 你能谈谈你在竞选材料中使用泄露的联邦数据的事吗? - 不能
Can you tell me anything about the breach of federal data used in your campaign material? - No.
你刚刚才说你要尽力协助调查
You said that you'd help this inquiry in any way.
对 我的确说了
Yes, and I have just then.
总统知道游说
Did the president know about the lobbying
让家庭第一提案不通过的事情吗?
against the Families First Bill?
我只是个无名小卒
I'm a nobody.
真的 我只是个小人物
That's the truth. I'm a nobody.
我只是个小人物 在总统耳边嘀咕几个名字
I'm just the guy that, like, whispers names
和告诉她人们的资料
to the president and I tell her facts about people.
所以说你只是一个提词人?
So you're just a prompter?
我是提词的人 这是真的
I'm a man who prompts, that is correct.
那么你说的关于
So all the talk of being the
那你是总统的信息渠道都是吹牛的?
president's pipeline was just bigheadedness?
没错 是的
Yeah. Yeah.
我是个自大的人
I'm an arrogant man.
我不是一个有权有势有过错的自大的人
I'm not a powerful, guilty, arrogant man.
我是个自大的人
I'm an arrogant man.
换句话说 你和说客都没有联系?
So you wouldn't have contact, in other words, with lobbyists?
不 不
No. No.
事实上 Catherine的未婚夫Jason是个说客
Actually, Catherine's fiance Jason is a lobbyist,
所以 我有时和说客有联系
so at times, yeah.
是么? 目前他还被认为是个顾问
Really? Until now he's been referred to as a consultant.
你对你女儿和一个说客订婚有顾虑吗?
Are you concerned with your daughter being engaged to a lobbyist?
证词
不 完全没有
No, not at all.
他也不是个真正的说客
And he's not actually a lobbyist.
他是个顾问 所以--
He's a consultant, so--
但是你的拎包人Gary Walsh
But your bagman Gary Walsh
说他是一个说客
referred to him as a lobbyist.
嗯 Gary的能力很有限
Um, Gary has a very limited set of skills.
他们工作的主要内容就是 把东西拿起来
Mainly I would say they are picking objects up
再原样放回去
and then putting objects back down.
他说他负责解决你的卫生问题
He said he takes care of your sanitary needs.
是这样吗?
Is that correct?
是-- 是-- 什么?
Yeah-- yeah-- what?
你说你女儿的未婚夫 Read先生不是说客
You say your daughter's fianc Mr. Read is not a lobbyist,
然而 Merryman & Cotter公司
and yet the firm of Merryman & Cotter
在公司官网"我们的说客"部分
lists him under the title of lobbyist
将他列在了说客名单上
in the "Our lobbyists" Section of its website.
那是他们的说辞 并不是我的说法
Well, that's their word. That's not my word.
他是基督教互援会 乐施会
He is a lobbyist for Christian Aid, Oxfam,
及世界卫生组织的说客
the World Health Organization.
嗯 无论你用哪种方式称呼他
Mm-hmm, well, he sounds like a decent guy,
听起来似乎都很体面
whatever you want to call him.
同时他还为医药企业
Also lobbying for pharmaceutical companies,
大型IT组织 投资银行进行游说
large IT organizations, investment banks.
是的 我未婚夫是说客
Yes, my fianc√? is a lobbyist.
这给你们的关系带来困难了吗?
Does that present any difficulties in your relationship?
除了我现在坐在一间屋子里
Not apart from the fact that I am now sitting in a room
对着一个镜头和两个陌生人谈论此事之外 并没有什么影响
with two strangers talking about it on camera.
你不喜欢被质问?
You don't like being questioned?
不喜欢被问及个人私生活 不 我并不喜欢
Not about my personal life, no, I don't.
难道你喜欢? 当然了 前提是你有私生活
I mean, do you? Assuming that you have one.
我看你手上没带戒指 所以...
I don't see that you're wearing a ring, so...
Meyer小姐 我们要稍微提醒一下我们是在做证词采集
Ms. Meyer, you're gently reminded that this is a deposition.
下一次我就不会这么客气了
I won't be as polite next time.
嗯 抱歉 我能休息一下吗?
Um, I'm sorry. Can I please take a minute?
可以 当然可以 - 谢谢
Sure, yeah. Of course. - Thank you.
刚才真是抱歉 我刚刚出去吃了点东西
I'm sorry about that. I just had to get a snack.
我低血糖 所以...
My blood sugar was dropping, so...
没事
That's okay.
你没觉得这里面存在利益冲突吗?
Do you not see the conflict of interest?
我是指 我们正在调查说客和你方政府
I mean, we are investigating direct links
之间的直接联系 - 是 我发现了
- between lobbyists and your administration. - Yes, I see it.
- 这难道和你无关吗?
- Does it not concern you?
- 如果你能让我说完我的话
- If you would just let me finish my sentence,
我会非常感激
that would be very much appreciated.
我确实知道这里面有冲突
I do see it.
同时我认为
It is also my understanding
他们可能已经解除婚约了
that they may no longer be engaged.
所以...
So...
他们分手了吗?
They've split up?
嗯 我想...
Um, I think...
他们可能已经分手了
they may have split up.
另外 我还想说的是 我真的不确定
In addition to that, I will say that I'm really not certain
Jason就是适合Catherin的那个人
that Jac-- Ja-- Jason was ever right for Catherine.
可你刚刚说过他人很好
But you just said that he was sweet.
呃-嗯 他有时候人是很好
Mm-hmm. He can be sweet at one moment
但他下一秒又会变得很强势
and then he can be very controlling in the next moment.
你懂的 为乐施会 还有医药公司游说
You know, lobbying for Oxfam, or then lobbying for PhRMA.
我是说 咨询
And I meant consulting.
我必须离开一下 我得给非洲总统打个电话
I have to go. I've got to call the president of Africa.
所以-- 我是指南非 你懂的 所以...
So-- I mean South Africa specifically, you know, so...
Wilson女士 我们了解到
Ms. Wilson, it has been said of you
你是个可以在组织诺曼底登陆战役的同时
that you could organize the D-Day landings
仍然有时间布置硫磺岛战役的人
and still have time left over for Iwo Jima.
而且 与现实有别的是 我布置的硫磺岛战役会赢得更轻松
And, unlike in reality, I would have gotten Iwo Jima right.
尽管如此 总统和
And yet this meeting between the president
议员Pierce的这次会议
and Congressman Pierce,
并没有出现在你的日程记录里
you have no record of that in your schedule.
Pierce议员和总统的会议并不倾向于
Congressman Pierce was not disposed
一个预示为会议的行为
in a manner that was indicative of a meeting.
我没听懂你这话是什么意思
I literally have no idea what that sentence means.
遇见某人和会见
There's a difference between
是有区别的
meeting someone and having a meeting with them.
我的意思是 我有一次遇见了Bill Gates
I mean, I once met Bill Gates,
但我并没有和他“开会”
but I didn't have a "Meeting" With him.
我们保留严谨且详尽的
We keep meticulous, exhaustive records
电子邮件和语音备忘录
of emails, voice memos,
以及短信 信件的记录
text messages, letters--
主席 我们有所有的电子邮件 信件 短信记录
Chairman, we have all the emails, letters, texts,
但你提到了语音备忘录 Wilson女士
but you mentioned voice memos, Ms. Wilson.
是的
Yes.
我们有各种不同的沟通形式
Well, we have many forms of communication.
现在看来
None of which you seem
你似乎不精通其中任何一种
to be able to master at the present moment.
我并不负责语音备忘录的管理
Well, I wasn't responsible for the voice memos.
- 那么谁是管理... - Mike McLintock
- So who would know about-- - Mike McLintock.
McLintock先生 请起立
Mr. McLintock, please rise
举起你的右手
and raise your right hand.
你是否向上帝庄严宣誓
Do you solemnly swear that
你尽其所知
the testimony you're about to give is the truth,
所述之言纯属实言并且无任何隐瞒?
the whole truth, and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
向上帝起誓 是的
So help me God. I do.
我们的一名正式的证人称
We have a witness go on record
看到你和Egan先生
saying that they saw you in the White House parking lot
Brookheimer女士 Pierce参议员曾一起出现在白宫停车场
with Mr. Egan, Ms. Brookheimer, and Senator Pierce.
没错
That's correct.
我碰巧遇到他们
I ran into them by chance
当时我只是去车里拿东西
because I was merely getting something from my car.
- 你当时去拿什么? - 什么?
- What were you getting? - I'm sorry?
你当时去拿什么?
What were you getting?
我去拿 拿药
Uh, I was getting some medicine.
什么药?
What kind of medicine?
膝盖药
Um, it's knee medicine.
膝盖药?
Knee medicine?
是的 膝盖药
Yeah, knee medicine.
用在 只用在一个膝盖上
For one of-- just one of my knees.
- 哪一个? - 哪一个膝盖吗?
- Which one? - Which knee?
我的左 左膝盖 法官大人 先生
My left-- left knee, Your Honor, sir.
我的左膝盖 我的左膝盖有问题
My left knee. I have problems with my left knee.
蹲下的时候会疼
Um, it hurts when I crouch.
药物的名字是什么?
What was the name of the medicine?
我想是叫...
Um, I want to say it's called...
蹲膏
Crouch Cream.
然而并不是这个名字
But that's not right.
是一个带红色标签的白色管子
It's a white tube with a red label.
一个实习生都能够查到这药
I'm sure an intern could research this.
有一个马的剪影在上面
It has a silhouette of a horse on it.
我不知道为什么要放个马在上面
I don't know why the horse is on there.
我猜可能是因为马的膝盖很强壮吧
I guess horses probably have good knees.
所以... 但我想它是叫...
So, um-- but I think it's called...
膝盖-Z 膝盖-Z膏
Knee-Z. Knee-Z Cream.
我想不是的 但是能搜到的
I don't think that's it. It's searchable.
我很确定
I'm very positive.
谢谢你允许我去处理那些总统事务
Thank you for allowing me to attend to presidential matters.
证词
我们仍然想询问关于您女儿和Read先生
We still wish to consider the outstanding issues
尚未说清楚的事情
concerning your daughter and Mr. Read.
他们确实已经分手了
Who have definitely split up.
我很烦乱 真的很难过
I'm quite undone. I'm really upset.
我在这段时间里越来越喜欢Jason
Um, I had grown quite fond of dear Jason.
您曾经说他对于您女儿太老了
You've said he's too old for your daughter
而且他有控制欲 还有双重人格
and that he can be controlling and that he has two personalities.
我有份声明要宣读
I have a statement I'm going to read.
我很难过的宣布
I am sad to confirm the end
我的女儿Catherine与Jason Read解除婚约
of my daughter Catherine's engagement to Jason Read.
这是由于一些私人原因
This was for personal reasons unconnected
与针对我方政府正在进行的调查没有关系
to the ongoing inquiries into my administration
不过调查可能给他们之间的关系
other than the strain said inquiries brought
带来了压力
upon their relationship.
今天对于真相来说是个日子
This may be a good day for truth,
但对于爱情却是伤心的一天
but a sad day for love.
你推荐了一个应用给总统
You recommended an app for the president,
- 是吗 - 是的 女士
- did you not? - Yes, ma'am.
你能在你的手机上演示一下如何使用这个应用吗?
Could you demonstrate how the app works on your phone?
是的 非常乐意
Yes, I'd be happy to.
你点开主页
So you go to your home screen, it's called.
记住这一点
Remember that.
现在你要决定发给谁
And now you have to send it to someone.
所以我要发给...
So I could send it to...
你能给我你的号码吗?
you want to give me your number?
- 要不我就发给我自己 - 好的
- Or I'll just send it to myself. - Fine.
现在我要做的就是恰当地
So now all I do is appropriately touch
触摸这个按钮来录音
the icon for record.
你好 Mike 我是Mike
And-- hey, Mike, it's Mike.
嗯...
Um...
你可能收不到
you're probably not going to get this
因为你正在一个听证会上 但是我...
'cause you're in the hearings, but I just...
- 想告诉你... - 足够了
- wanted to tell you-- - That's quite enough.
我得挂了 Mike
I've got to go, Mike.
然后只要按发送键
And then you just press send.
它就会马上出现在我的备忘录应用里了
And it should instantly appear on my memo app.
怎么没有 呃 我也不知道怎么回事
Which it's not doing. Um, I don't know why.
大概这就是为什么他们
I guess that's why they
说不要和动物或科技一起工作吧
say don't work with animals or technology.
所以的拍摄过程才如此可怕
I mean, that's why "Jaws" Was such a nightmare shoot.
我指的是 机器鲨鱼 当我没说
I mean, mechanical shark, forget it.
哦 膝盖无忧 这就是药的名字
Oh, Knee Free. That's the cream.
膝盖无忧 你只要--
- Knee Free, if you-- -
好了 听吧
Okay, here it is.
-- 你好 Mike 我是Mike
And-- hey, Mike, it's Mike.
嗯...
Um...
你可能收不到
you're probably not going to get this
因为你正在一个听证会上 但是...
'cause you're in the hearings, but--
还挺清晰的
Pretty good clarity.
我们能听几句总统发的消息吗?
Could we hear some of the messages that the president sent?
不行 因为我删掉了信息 都被我删掉了
No, because I deleted them. They're deleted.
说实话 都是关于
I mean, truthfully, these things were just
她谈论些止疼药什么的 没什么重要的
her talking about Advil and lemons.
我们听的时候会进行判断
Well, we'll see how many when we listen to them.
很抱歉 先生 我都删掉了
Sadly, sir, I deleted those.
我知道 但是云端不是还有吗
Yeah, but they still exist in the cloud,
你应该很清楚这一点吧
as I'm sure you're aware.
Ben Dan和Amy在上了吗?
Selina's voice: Ben, are Dan and Amy on course?
这绝不可能
It can't happen.
呃 这可以指的东西可多了
Well, that could be about anything.
可能是说他们...
Probably about them...
比如 性交
you know, mating.
说这不可能?
And it can't happen?
是说我们绝不可能选举失败
It can't happen that we lose this vote.
是不是你觉得有点牵强了?
Or is that too far-fetched for you?
好吧 那她为什么会提到这个?
Well, why did she mention it, then?
呃 她当时在发烧 不太清醒
Well, she was feverish.
所以你是说以她当时状态不适合管理国家是吗?
So you're saying she wasn't in a fit state to govern?
不 我可没这么说
No, I'm not saying that.
如果我要这么说的话 那我当时就说了
If I was saying that, then that's what I would have said.
我是说 你为啥要妄想拿石头攻击一辆坦克呢?
I mean, why are you throwing pebbles at a tank?
别这样了
Stop.
你要知道 就算是麻疯病(腐败)You know, that lady, she could govern herself
也丝毫不能影响那位女士的工作
rough leprosy.
您是怎样看待您和
How would you characterize your friendship
议员Bennett之间的友谊的呢?
with Congresswoman Bennett?
呃 我倒不觉得我们是朋友
Uh, well, I wouldn't say that we're friends.
或许说我们之间很友好更合适
I would say that we are friendly.
所以她在委员会里 并不会刻意回避
So she's not on the committee to steer them away
对您不利的话题 对吗?
from issues that might be uncomfortable for you?
不会 嗯
No. Mm-mmm.
我可是总统
I'm president.
我没有时间来经营友情
I don't have time for friends.
总统女士 是您
Madam President, it was you
指定了一位特别检察官
who appointed a special prosecutor
特别检察官：专职调查牵涉总统的舞弊案 以避免调查过程会受到政府高层及执政党的干涉
而我们的团队归这位特检官管辖
and we are the team under your appointee.
嗯 没错
Yeah, well, there you go.
Ryan先生
- Mr. Ryan.
委员会注意到
It has come to this committee's attention
你在表决家庭第一提案前
that you suffered some emotional issues
情绪有很大波动
during the run-up to the Families First Bill.
我被人摸了
I was touched.
被谁?
Who touched you?
我现在不想说
I would rather not say at this time.
以后也不想
Or any.
能告诉我们原因吗?
Can you give us a reason why?
抱歉 耽搁两分钟
Excuse me for one moment.
我嘴巴很-很干
I just have a very-- a very dry mouth.
不需要指明身份...
Setting their identity aside...
不需要指明身份
Setting their identity aside,
你在哪儿被此人摸了?
where did this person touch you?
呃...
Um...
是摸了我的私处
he touched me in a private place.
能再明确点吗? 摸的是你的屁股吗?
Can you be more specific? Was it the buttocks?
不 不
No. No.
是 -是另一面
It was-- it was around the other side.
那就是胯部了
The crotch, presumably.
那请问
Was there ever any contact
睾丸和手之间有接触吗?
between testicles and hands?
够了 拜托
Okay, listen,
要判断的不是有没有游说吗?
I thought that this was supposed to be about lobbying.
很明显 这位国会女议员所问的问题
And it seems clear that the congresswoman
已经偏离了此次听证会的主题
is pulling focus away from the main concern of this panel.
就像Brookheimer女士的穿着打扮一样
Similarly with Ms. Brookheimer's dress.
她自己都无法相信这一身服装是得体的
She can't have believed that this would work.
她看上去从未如此谦逊过
She never looks this humble.
我不 我不清楚你在影射什么 Ryan先生
I'm not-- I'm not sure what you're referring to, Mr. Ryan.
我的日常着装就是这样的
This is my everyday attire.
如果这冒犯了您 我非常抱歉 但
And I apologize if it offends you, but...
你们看到她刚才的动作了
But you saw what she just did with the--
你们都看到了对吧
I mean, you saw that.
她在玩弄你们 好像你们是廉价的
She is playing you like a cheap--
- 说话注意点  - 就像微软游戏机一样
- Careful. - Like an Xbox.
Ryan先生 相信我 没有人在玩弄我们  我们是不容摆布的
Mr. Ryan, trust me, no one is playing us. We are unplayable.
我想听听关于性骚扰指控的更多细节
I'd like to hear more on the charges of molestation.
请继续
Go ahead.
我想听听关于性骚扰指控的更多细节
I'd like to hear more on the charges of molestation.
请继续
Go ahead.
他的手曾经接触过你的睾丸吗?
Was there ever any contact between testicles and hands?
不 没有
No. Never.
我的 蛋蛋们
My... spheres
一向穿戴整齐
were always clothed.
我当时在工作场所 所以我
I was in the workplace, so I--
他总会同时摸你的两个睾丸吗?
Did he always grope both testicles?
不好意思 能换一个男委员
I'm sorry, but can I be asked that question
来问我这种问题吗?
by a male committee member?
不 由我来问
No, I asked the question.
很抱歉  我忘了你的问题是什么
I'm sorry. I forgot the question.
那个欺凌你的人是不是摸了你的两个睾丸?
Did your abuser touch both of your testicles?
- 谢谢你 Egan先生  - 不客气
- Thank you, Mr. Egan. - Sure.
在你的白宫任职期间 还有谁知道这件事情？
Who else was aware of this during your time at the White House?
我 我也亲眼见过
I, uh-- I also saw it.
我没法
I can't stop--
我没法不去想它
I can't stop thinking about it.
这 你知道的 就像一个警铃
It's-- you know, it's like a bell.
声响无法停止
It can't be unrung.
这件事发生在哪里
Where did you see it happen?
在他的蛋蛋附近
It was around the spheres.
我是问你是在哪儿目睹了这件事
I meant what area of the workplace.
哦 对 不好意思 没错
Oh, yes. No, I'm sorry. Yes.
在一条走廊上
It was in a hallway.
和Dan看到的是同一次
Same time as Dan.
事实上 他当时正准备炒了Jonah
In fact, he was coming to fire Jonah as a scapegoat
让他做儿童死亡率数据泄露的替罪羊
for the child mortality data breach. Oh!
- 很好 没有其他问题了 - 等下 等下
- Okay, there's no further questions. - Whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
等下 等下  你能再复述一遍刚才的话吗? Splett先生
Wait, wait. Can you repeat that, Mr. Splett?
实际上 我希望引用宪法第五条修正案
Uh, actually, I'd like to plead the fifth.
拒不申辩 以免自证其罪
I'd like to plead the fifth, please.
Splett先生 你可以复述
Mr. Splett, can you repeat--
你可以复述一下刚才所说的话吗? Splett先生
can you repeat what you just said, Mr. Splett?
- 我们正在调查一项关于滥用权力... - 女议员
- We were investigating a serious allegation... - Congresswoman.
- 的严重指控 - 好了!
- ...of abuse in the-- - Please!
你能重复一下你刚才所说的话吗? Splett先生
Can you repeat what you just said, Mr. Splett?
是的 可以 我希望引用宪法第五条修正案
Yes, I can. I'd like to plead the fifth.
- 在那之前的话 - 好吧
- Before that. - Okay.
我认为 我刚才误说了
Uh, I think I mistakenly said
Dan将Jonah推出去 作为儿童死亡率
that Dan was scapegoating Jonah
数据泄露的替罪羊
for the child mortality data breach.
你能告诉我们
Can you tell us who was
谁才应该为这个数据泄露负责吗? Cafferty先生
responsible for the data breach, Mr. Cafferty?
不能
No.
但你的确知道谁对此事负有责任 对吗?
But you do know who was responsible?
不知道
No.
你能告诉我们任何关于数据泄露的情况吗?
Can you tell us anything at all about said data breach?
不能
No.
你想继续用同一个答案
Are you gonna continue to answer every question
来回答所有的问题吗? Cafferty先生
with a one-word answer, Mr. Cafferty?
不想
No.
我并不想
I am not.
好吧 这毫无意义
Okay, that means nothing.
我们需要你说出责任人 否则本届政府会惹上大麻烦
We need a name or this administration is in big trouble.
Gary Walsh 听过这个名字吗?
Gary Walsh, any thoughts?
证   词
我不知道那是谁
I don't know who that is.
谁啊 Gary
Who-- Gary?
Walsh
Walsh.
哦 是那个
Oh, the-- yeah.
参议员 你认为Gary Walsh
Senator, do you think it's possible
是否有可能就是那个给Egan先生
Gary Walsh was responsible for making payments
与Brookheimer女士行贿 (让他们进行反对家庭第一提案的游说的人)
to Mr. Egan and Ms. Brookheimer
去游说别人反对家庭第一法案？
to lobby against the Families First Bill?
请原谅我觉得这个想法很可笑
Forgive me for laughing at the notion.
你得明白 Gary Walsh
Gary Walsh, you need to understand,
就是个被困在12岁女孩身体里的一个12岁男孩
is a 12-year-old boy trapped in the body of a 12-year-old girl.
你有没有在Amy Brookheimer和Daniel Clifford Egan
Did you contact Amy Brookheimer and Daniel Clifford Egan
离开白宫后
after they had left the White
因为家庭第一法案的事联系过他们？
House with regard to the Families First Bill?
联系过
I did.
你是否同意给他们钱
Did you agree to pay them to lobby
让他们代表总统去游说别人反对这一法案？
against the bill on behalf of the president?
没有 没有 没有 没有 我没有
Nope. Nope, nope, nope, nope. No, I did not.
那么有没有其他人安排了这件事呢？
So did somebody else make this arrangement?
Bill Ericsson
Bill Ericsson.
-你能让我把问题问完吗？ -好的
- Will you let me finish my question? - Mm-hmm.
有没有其他人安排了这次付款？
Someone else arranged to make such a payment?
有
Yes.
- 是谁 - Bill
- Who was it? - Bill.
Bill?
Bill...?
Ericsson
Ericsson.
是联络主管Bill Ericsson
It was the director of communications Bill Ericsson.
没有人要求你说是Ericsson 对吧?
You haven't been asked to say Ericsson, have you?
没有
No.
我相信应该是Bill Ericsson
I believe that Bill Ericsson
一直在负责这方面的工作
would have been overseeing that aspect.
- Bill Ericsson - Bill Ericsson
- Bill Ericsson. - Bill Ericsson.
- Bill Ericsson先生 - Bill Ericsson
- Mr. Bill Ericsson. - Bill Ericsson.
- 是的 Bill Ericsson -听我说
- Yes, Bill Ericsson. - You listen to me.
我涉足政坛是因为我有很清晰的识别能力
I got into politics because I have a very clear sense,
我能非常敏锐地识别出什么是对的什么是错的 好吗？
a burning sense of what is right and what is good, all right?
我不是律师 我不会指责别人
I'm not an attorney, I don't point the finger,
我不会推卸责任 我不是这样的人
I don't lay blame, that's not who I am.
但对你的问题我的回应是 没错
But in answer to your question, yes,
Bill Ericsson挪用了基金
Bill Ericsson used misappropriated funds
去让别人反对总统的法案
to lobby against the president's bill.
这简直是一个噩梦
This is a nightmare.
我可能会面临刑事起诉
I'm probably gonna be facing criminal charges.
- 你认为你自己是无辜的？ - 我是无辜的
- You consider yourself innocent? - I am innocent.
你是想让我脱掉衣服
Do you want me to take off my shirt
给你看看
so that you can see all
我背上有多少刀把儿吗？
the knife handles sticking out of my back?
Bennett议员去哪儿了？
Where is Congresswoman Bennett?
她离席了
She is absent.
是的 我注意到了
Yes, I got that.
我高中的时候上过“注意”这门课
I took noticing in high school.
我觉得现在真正的问题是Bill Ericsson
I think the real issue now is Bill Ericsson
还有他可能做过的事
and what he may have done
或者没做过的事
or what he may not have done
以及他的可耻行径影响 或者没有
and how his rogue actions did or did not
影响到很多人
affect so many lives.
当然了 这得你们自己来判定
But that is, of course, for you to determine yourselves.
你只是在做他们想让你做的事
You're only doing what they want you to do.
你很清楚这一点 对吧
You are aware of that, right?
这就像我在祭坛上
It's like I'm on the sacrificial altar
突然间所有人都戴上了头罩
and suddenly everyone is wearing hoods.
那天你不仅取笑了我的身高
The other day you had fun with my size
还因为我的身高而给我起了外号
and the nicknames that you gave me about my size.
高·麦卡特尼
Tall McCartney.
摩天大楼
Skyscraper.
不过Jonah Ryan是坚强的
But Jonah Ryan is strong.
只要Jonah Ryan能帮到一个人
And if Jonah Ryan can help one man
任何一个遭遇工作场合性骚扰的人
who is dealing with workplace sexual harassment,
那么这所有的苦难和折磨就都是值得的
then this entire ordeal will have been worth it.
大家拭目以待吧 谢谢
Watch this space. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
知道吗 现在在停车场角落里
You know, there are probably fairer trials happening
可能有更公平的审判正在进行
right now in the back of parking lots
被告人头上套着布袋的那种
where the defendant is wearing a mailbag on his head.
请举起你的右手
Please raise your right hand.
你的右手
Your right hand.
抱歉 我是对着镜子练习的
Sorry, I was practicing in the mirror.
你是否向上帝发誓
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you're about to give
你尽其所知
is the truth, the whole truth,
所述之言纯属实言并且无任何隐瞒?
and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
当然 说这个太激动啦
Absolutely. Excited to do it.